Now assume there is a car that is totally lost,
假设有一辆车彻底丢了
which means you, as a driver or as a car,
也就是说 作为驾驶员或车辆
have no clue where you are.
完全不知道自己在哪里
Now you assume that you have a global map of the environment.
现在 你假设你有一副全球环境地图
In this example, you can see a map
在本例中 你可以看到一张位于森尼韦尔的
of the environment around the [INAUDIBLE] office
梅赛德斯办公楼的
in [INAUDIBLE].
周边环境
Now, generally speaking, localization
一般而言 定位回答的问题是
answers a question, where is our car in a given
在一副高精度的地图上
map with a high accuracy?
我的车在哪里？
And high accuracy means between three and 10 centimeters.
高精度是指 3 到 10 厘米
In a traditional way, we use global navigation satellite
传统上 我们使用全球导航卫星系统来
systems to find the car, with respect to the map.
查找汽车在地图上的位置
But GPS is not precise enough.
但是 GPS 精确度不够
Most of the time, GPS has an accuracy
很多时候 GPS 测量车道宽度的准确度为
of the worth of a lane-- about one to three meters.
大约 1 到 3 米
But sometimes it can be as broad as 10 to 50 meters.
但有时候 可能宽达 10 到 50 米
Clearly this is not reliable enough for a self-driving car.
很显然 这对无人驾驶车来说是不够可靠的
So you can't trust GPS.
因此 你不能信任 GPS
And you have to find another technique to localize yourself
你必须想一个其他方法 找出你自己
inside a given map.
在给定地图上的位置
It is common practice to use the onboard sensor
常用的做法是 使用车载传感器数据
data, along with our global map, to solve the localization
以及我们的全球地图 来解决
issue.
定位问题
So with the onboard sensors it is
车载传感器
possible to measure distances to static obstacles,
可以测量车辆到静态障碍物的距离
like trees, poles, or walls.
如树木、杆子或墙壁
We measure these distances, and the bearing
我们测量这些距离 以及这些静态
of these static objects in the local
物体在车辆的本地坐标系中
coordinate system of our car.
的方向
Now when you're lucky, the same obstacles
如果你比较幸运 你通过车载传感器
that were observed by the onboard sensors
观察到的障碍物可能也在
are also part of the map.
地图上
And, of course, the map has its own global coordinate system.
当然 地图有自己的全球坐标系
To estimate where the car is in the map,
要估算车辆在地图中的位置
you have to match the observations
你必须把观察结果和
with the map information.
地图信息相匹配
And when you do it correctly, this results
如果操作正确
in a transformation between both coordinate systems--
就能实现两个坐标系之间的转换
the local car coordinate system and the global coordinate
车辆的本地坐标系和地图的
system of the map.
全球坐标系
This transformation should be as accurate
转换应尽可能准确
as possible-- let's say within a range of 10 centimeters
比如 误差为 10 厘米
or less.
或更低
If you are able to estimate this transformation,
如果你能估算这种转换
you solve the localization issue.
你就解决了定位问题
So after this example, we can summarize.
我们总结一下这个例子
First, localization answers the question
首先 定位回答的问题是
of where the car is in a given map within an accuracy of 10
车辆在给定地图上的位置 而且精确度必须为 10
centimeters or less.
厘米或更高
And second, onboard sensors are used
其次 车载传感器可用于
to estimate the transformation between local measurements
估算本地测量值和给定地图之间
and a given map.
的转换